When he fell into silence, movies gave him back his voice
Life, Animated is a documentary film directed by Roger Ross Williams.
At three years old, a chatty, energetic little boy named Owen Suskind ceased
to speak, disappearing into autism with apparently no way out.
Almost four years passed and the only stimuli that
engaged Owen were Disney films.
Then one day, his father donned a puppet—Iago, the wisecracking parrot
from Aladdin—and asked “what’s it like to be you?” And poof!
Owen replied, with dialogue from the movie.
Life, Animated tells the remarkable story of how Owen found in Disney animation a
pathway to language and a framework for making sense of the world.
Himself, played by Owen Suskind.
Himself, played by Ron Suskind.
Himself, played by Jonathan Freeman.
Himself, played by Gilbert Gottfried.
Life, Animated is a 2016  American independent
documentary film by director Roger Ross Williams.
It is co-produced by Williams with Julie Goldman,
Carolyn Hepburn and Christopher Clements.
Life, Animated is based on journalist Ron Suskind's 2014 book Life, Animated: A Story of Sidekicks, Heroes, and Autism, which tells the story of his son,
Owen Suskind, who struggles with autism and learned how to communicate with the outside world through his love of Disney animated films.
Upon its release, the film received generally positive reviews from critics and won numerous awards including
the Sundance Film Festival award for Best Direction and the Special Achievement Annie Award.
It was also nominated for the Academy Award for Best Documentary Feature Film
category at the 89th Academy Awards, but lost to O.J.: Made in America.
The film explores themes of autism, candid,
inspirational, awestruck, empathetic.
The tone is uplifting.